Why have I never thought
我怎么从没想到
that Ichiko could also have an affair?
小一也可能会有婚外情呢？
Today is the third Thursday of the month.
今天是这个月的第三个周四
The one night out of the month
是我老公每月一次
my husband sleeps with his lover.
和情人过夜的日子
And today
今天
marks the very first time I'm visiting a brothel.
我第一次去风俗馆
BASED ON THE MANGA "1122" BY PEKO WATANABE
（根据渡边平子同名漫画改编）
1122: FOR A HAPPY MARRIAGE
电视剧名：1122 好夫妻
Congratulations.
恭喜
Thank you very much.
谢谢
-Congratulations. -Thank you. It's so nice to meet you.
-恭喜 -谢谢 见到你真高兴
Nice to meet you too.
我也是
I saw it.
我看到了
You made a wonderful website for that store in Uehara.
你帮上原那家店做的网站特别好
-You showed her? -Sorry, it was so good that I had to.
-你给她看了？ -对不起 实在太好了 所以没忍住
-How embarrassing. -I thought it was so cute.
-好难为情 -真的好可爱
Thank you. It was a struggle to finish it.
谢谢 好不容易才做出来
-Really? -The store is really nice too.
-是吗？ -那家店也很不错
You should visit it. It's really cute.
有空去逛逛 超可爱的
Are you Ichiko Yamane?
山根小姐？
Otoya Aihara?
相原先生？
-Did you know each other? -Yeah.
-你们认识？ -嗯
Wait, you two are acquainted? From work?
你们认识？因为工作？
Yeah, she made my company's website.
嗯 她帮我们公司做了网站
And I was in the same club as Taro in college.
我和太郎大学时是一个社团的
So, you were in the same club.
是这样啊
Otoya, you actually have a job, huh?
二也 你真有正经工作啊？
What did you think I'd do?
不然你以为呢？
Let me ask you, what did you think I'd think you would do?
你说我怎么以为？
Of course I have a job.
我当然有工作
Hey, Otoya. It's been a long time.
相原君 好久不见
Yeah, it has.
是啊 好久不见
This is Ichiko Yamane, a web designer.
这位是山根小姐 网站设计师
-Nice to meet you. -Hello.
-幸会 -你好
I'm Aiko Mizuno. I'm an editor for Koensha.
我是水野爱子 在讲苑社担任编辑
I went to college with Otoya.
我和相原君是大学同学
Actually, Otoya, what do you do?
对了 相原君 你现在做什么工作？
I work for a stationery brand.
我在一家文具公司工作
What's it called?
叫什么名字？
White Bambi.
白斑比
Never heard of it.
从没听说过
Didn't you want to work in media or TV?
你当初不是 想进媒体或电视行业的吗？
I probably said something like that.
好像是这么说过
Not "probably," you did.
不是“好像” 就是说过
You haven't changed a bit.
你真是一点也没变
You've always been forgetful and wishy-washy.
总是忘东忘西 优柔寡断
On top of that--
不仅如此…
Otoya, there's someone over there who wants to say hi to you.
相原君 那边有人想跟你打个招呼
Shall we go?
我们可以过去吗？
Sorry, Aiko.
抱歉 水野小姐
Sure.
好的
This is a beautiful place, but they have a small drinks menu.
这地方很漂亮 但饮料的种类很少
So, where is that person who wanted to talk to me?
你说想跟我打招呼的人呢？
That was a lie.
我瞎说的
-What? -Sorry, I just couldn't stand it, so…
对不起 实在听不下去了 所以就…
I was getting annoyed and angry just watching you two.
光是看你俩说话 我就一肚子火
Well, she is my ex.
她是我前女友
I see.
原来如此
I'm sorry you saw something ugly.
不好意思 让你见笑了
No, it's not a big deal.
不 没什么大不了的
You shouldn't listen to that without saying a word.
可你也不能那样光听着 什么也不说呀
That might be true.
说的也是
It was a messy break up,
分手时 我们闹得很不愉快
so I thought she might still be mad at me.
所以她大概还在生我的气吧
And that made you happy?
所以你很开心吗？
Oh, no. That's never going to happen.
没有 完全没有的事
-Anyway, you're too nice of a person. -No, I'm just indecisive.
-总之 你还是太好说话了 -不 我只是优柔寡断
And I'm also
而且
forgetful and wishy-washy.
还健忘 总忘东忘西
I guess she cut you deeply.
看来她的话很有杀伤力
Ichiko, want to get out of here and have a drink with me?
山根小姐 我们另找个地方喝一杯吧？
It's on me.
我请客
Yeah.
好啊
This is…
这是…
Are you familiar with this area?
这附近你熟悉吗？
Not really.
不太熟
Is there a place you know?
你有熟悉的店吗？
Kind of.
算是吧
"Kind of."
“算是”
How about this one? I've been meaning to try it.
这里怎么样？我一直想试试
Let's go in.
那我们进去吧
-Are you sure? -Yeah.
-可以吗？ -嗯
Okay.
好
-To a good night.
-辛苦了
-Cheers.
-干杯
-It's good. -Yeah.
-好喝 -嗯
Have you been together for long?
你们俩在一起很久了吗？
Your relationship.
交往多久了？
-No. -We're not dating.
-不是的 -我们没在交往
-My apologies. -No, it's okay.
-对不起 -没事
Since you look good together.
因为你们俩看起来很般配
Thank you.
谢谢
This is embarrassing.
好难为情
-Yeah, it is. -Yeah.
-是挺难为情的 -是的
That day, I was a little excited.
那天 我有点兴奋
Otoya, a man I met through work,
因为工作而接触的相原君
asked me out for drinks.
请我喝酒
-I was kind of attracted to him. -Why did you get into your line of work?
-我稍微有点喜欢他 -你为什么做这行？
-My job? -Yeah.
-我的工作？ -嗯
But I think it's fun.
但我觉得很有意思
So, I probably like what I do.
所以我可能挺喜欢这行的
That's great.
那很好啊
-You think so? -Yes.
-是吗？ -是的
Ichiko was so pretty and cheerful.
小一漂亮又开朗
To me, she was sparkling beautifully in that dark bar.
在昏暗的酒吧里 她似乎闪闪发光
And now,
而现在
here I am.
我到了这里
here this is.
出现了这个
-Just how did we get here?
-我们怎么会走到这一步？
Ouch.
疼
Oh, no. Ouch.
好疼啊
Crap. Ouch--
好疼
Shit. This is bad.
糟糕了
Shit. Shit. Shit.
糟糕
Ouch. Shit.
糟了
Coming.
来了
-Good evening.
-晚上好
-Sorry to make you wait. -No.
-抱歉让你久等了 -没有
Wow, this is amazing.
好漂亮
It's so big. There's even a canopy.
这么大 还有床帐
Ichiko, thank you for getting such a beautiful hotel room.
一子 感谢你定了这么漂亮的房间
You're welcome.
不用客气
Shall we sit first?
我们先坐下吧？
This is for you, Ichiko.
这是送你的 一子
It's from a Kyoto candy maker.
是京都一家糖果店做的
It's so cute.
好可爱
Thank you.
谢谢你
Here.
来
Is it good?
好吃吗？
Yeah.
好吃
I'll answer any questions you have. So go ahead and ask.
有什么问题尽管问吧 我会一一解答
Since it's your first time.
因为你是第一次
Rei,
礼君
what do you do?
你是做什么的？
I go to college during the day.
我白天是大学生
So you're a student.
你是学生呀
Don't worry, I'm definitely over 20.
放心 我绝对年满20了
Oh, right.
哦 对了
I've been practicing my massage skills.
我最近在练习按摩技巧
Want to give it a try?
想试试吗？
Come over here.
那过来吧
That feels good.
很舒服
Your neck and back are stiff.
你的脖子和背部很僵硬
Do you strain your eyes at work?
工作时经常用眼吗？
I use a computer.
我要看电脑
I knew it.
果然
Shall we go to the bed?
我们去床上吧？
Hold on to me.
抱紧我
Here we go.
走咯
Can I kiss you?
我可以亲你吗？
You taste sweet.
你的味道好甜
It's okay. It's just a text.
没关系 短信而已
Sorry. I'll put it on silent mode.
对不起 我这就调成静音
Everything okay?
一切都好吗？
My…
那个…
My husband threw out his back.
我老公扭伤了腰
Okay.
这样啊
Is he okay?
要不要紧？
Looks like he's resting at home,
应该正在家里休息
but he sounds like he's in pain.
好像很疼的样子
I see.
这样啊
That's worrisome.
真让人担心
Ichiko, what do you want to do?
一子你想做什么？
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm just worried about him.
我放心不下他
Of course.
那是自然
I'll leave the money here.
我会把钱留下
-No need. Since I didn't do anything. -No, I can't.
-不用 我还什么都没做 -那可不行
Anyway, it's too bad, but there's no helping it.
总之 真遗憾啊 但也没办法
Hey.
那个…
Kiss me again.
再亲我一次
Ichiko.
一子
I don't need the fee for today,
今天我不收费
so I hope you'll book me again.
希望下次你能再指名我
Thank you.
谢谢你
I'm home.
我回来了
Otoyan.
二也
Otoyan?
二也？
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
Ichiko.
小一
How is your back?
腰怎么样了？
It really hurts. So much that I went numb.
很疼 疼得都快麻木了
And the hospital?
看医生了吗？
I went. They gave me pain meds and pain relief patches.
看了 给我开了止疼药和止疼贴
Did you eat?
吃过饭了吗？
Nope.
没有
Want a banana?
想吃根香蕉吗？
Yes.
想
Wait a second.
稍等一下
Ichiko.
小一
Thank you for coming back.
谢谢你赶回来
Sorry, I know you're busy.
对不起 我知道你很忙
Hey, Ichiko.
小一
Never mind.
没什么
-That's cold. -Sorry, sorry, sorry.
-好凉 -对不起
Okay, wait. What is it?
什么？
I was thinking that
我在想
it's so reassuring to have someone who knows me well
生病或者不舒服时 有贴心的人
be there for me when I'm in pain or feeling bad.
陪在身边 真让人安心
I'm really grateful.
真是多谢你了
We're married.
我们是夫妻嘛
That means we're a team.
当然要患难与共
-Can you put your feet down? -Yeah.
-可以把脚放下吗？ -嗯
Okay, feet down. Oh, yeah. Here?
好 把脚放下 这里？
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Ouch, ouch, ouch.
好疼
You good?
还好吗？
-Hands up. -Okay.
-手举起来 -嗯
Okay.
好了
Is this what happens when you get old?
人老了就是这样的吗？
I'll take really good care of you.
我以后一定会好好照顾你
Then I'll be counting on you when it happens to me.
那到时候就拜托你了
-Okay. -All right.
-好的 -好
-You okay? I'll take that. -Yeah.
-可以吗？给我吧 -嗯
You can do it. Yeah, you can do it.
加油 你可以的
Okay.
好
You did it.
你做到了
Yeah. Thanks.
谢谢你
You okay?
你还好吗？
I know this is not love.
我知道那不是爱
But you know what, Otoyan?
可你知道吗 二也？
I can kind of understand
现在我有点理解
what you must be feeling falling in love with someone else.
你爱上别人时 是什么感觉了
But this is
但这是
my own little secret.
我的秘密
You went to a brothel?
你去风俗馆了？
Hey, you're too loud.
你太大声啦
Sorry. I'm sorry.
抱歉 不好意思
I'm so, so sorry.
真对不起
What do you think about me going to one?
你对这件事有什么想法？
It's good. A great idea.
很好啊 是个好主意
Wait, how was it?
等等 怎么样？
What kind of man was it?
是什么样的男人？
Well,
这个嘛…
he was gorgeous.
长得特别帅
-Seriously? -Like a work of art.
-真的？ -非常俊美
Art?
俊美？
So it wasn't an urban myth.
这么说 不是都市传说啊
But he was urban-myth-level hot.
但他是都市传说级别的颜值
And?
然后呢？
How was it? In bed?
怎么样？在床上？
Actually,
其实呢
Otoyan threw out his back right at that moment.
就在关键时刻 二也扭伤了腰
I left right away.
我就立马走人了
What?
什么？
Wait, so, do you have regrets or not?
等等 那你有没有觉得遗憾？
Both, I think.
有点矛盾吧
I wasn't so sure about it and felt kind of guilty.
我对这件事不是很确定 有一种罪恶感
-Guilty? Because of Otoya? -Yeah.
-罪恶感？因为二也吗？ -嗯
Why? He's doing whatever he wants,
为什么？他可以为所欲为
so wouldn't it be considered fair by the Aihara rules
那一子按照相原家的规矩 也有婚外恋的权利
for you to exercise your right to have an affair?
这不是理所当然的吗？
It technically is,
严格说来是这样
but I don't want Otoyan to find out.
但我不想让二也知道
-About going to a brothel? -Yeah.
-去风俗馆的事？ -嗯
I think a person's sexuality is something completely personal and private,
我觉得无论是家人还是恋人
even if they have a family or a lover.
性都是非常私人的事情
So it's too embarrassing if he knows all the little details.
所以细节他都知道的话 就太尴尬了
Otoyan probably feels the same way,
二也可能也有同感
so whether we're having an affair or not,
所以无论有没有外遇
our sex lives are our own private lives.
我们的性生活都属于个人隐私
So I thought we could keep things separate
所以我原本以为 如果允许对方有婚外情的话
if we gave each other permission to have affairs, but now…
就不会影响到婚姻生活 但现在…
Then it's impossible for you to be open about your affair?
那你绝对不会坦白你的婚外情？
You'll stop?
就此打住？
I'm testing it out.
我还处于尝试阶段
Then you'll continue it?
那你会继续下去？
Because I might find the answer
因为可能在这种混乱之中
to a stable and long-lasting marriage through all this confusion.
能找到实现稳定长久婚姻的诀窍
Marriage is hard.
婚姻真难啊
Yeah, it is.
是好难
Confusion, huh? Isn't it too chaotic?
混乱啊 是不是有点太乱了？
It might be a little too chaotic.
可能有点太乱了
Welcome.
欢迎光临
-Sorry I'm late. -It's okay.
-抱歉我来晚了 -没事
-It's so cold today. -Yeah.
-今天真冷啊 -是啊
How's your back?
你的腰怎么样了？
Much better.
好多了
But it's still hard to sit for a long time.
但还是不能久坐
-Oh, okay. -Yeah.
-这样啊 -嗯
Then let's go home early today.
那今天早点回家吧
Welcome.
欢迎光临
I'd like a lemon tea.
我要一杯柠檬茶
It will be right out.
马上就来
What was the flower for today?
今天插了什么花？
Dendrobium orchid and golden willow.
石斛兰和金柳
The teacher looked sad that you missed the class.
你没来 老师好像很难过呢
You think you can go next week?
下周能来吗？
Yeah. I think I'll be better by next week.
嗯 下周应该会好很多
Actually,
话说
sorry about today.
今天对不起了
For what?
为什么？
Since we can't go to a hotel.
因为不能去开房
It's fine. It's not important.
没关系 那不重要
I mean, it's important,
不 其实是重要的
but were you worried about that?
难道你在担心这个？
A little.
有一点
Then let's take it slow next time.
那下次我们慢慢来
I'm fine if we can't do it for a while.
暂时不能做的话 我不介意
But it was a little hard
但你受了伤
not being able to help you when you're hurt.
我却不能照顾你 这让我有点伤心
Thank you for waiting. Here is your lemon tea.
久等了 您的柠檬茶
Thank you.
谢谢
It's natural since we both have our own families.
我们都有家人 所以这也是难免的
This is the first time I regret
如果不是情人 而是夫妻就好了
that this is an affair and that we're not married.
我是第一次有这种想法
Otoya.
二也
Yes?
嗯
Is it okay if I ask you an absurd question?
我能问你一个荒唐的问题吗？
An absurd…
荒唐的…
Go ahead.
问吧
Is it impossible for me, my son,
有没有可能 我和我的儿子
and you…
还有你…
For the three of us to live together?
我们三个在一起生活？
Mitsuki.
美月
I don't
我并不想
want to pry into your family life, but…
打探你的家事 但…
did something happen with your husband?
你丈夫是不是出了什么事？
Nothing happened.
什么事也没有
Sorry for surprising you with that.
抱歉突然问这种冒昧的问题
It's not like anything special happened.
并没有发生什么特别的事
I've been stressed out lately.
只是最近压力很大
About Hiro, and…
操心小宏 还有…
You can't talk with your husband about it?
你不能和你丈夫谈这些吗？
He's busy
他很忙
and doesn't seem to have the time.
好像抽不出时间
I see.
这样啊
I was thinking about going back to work.
我正在考虑重新开始工作
Part time.
做些兼职
-Really? -Yeah.
-是吗？ -嗯
Hiro seems to like his class,
小宏在特教班上好像适应得不错
and things have settled down,
情况已经比较稳定
so I was thinking about changing my environment a bit.
所以我在考虑换个环境
Yeah. I think it's a good idea.
我觉得这主意不错
You used to live abroad, and didn't you used to be a translator?
你以前在国外生活过 你不是做过翻译吗？
But it's really hard, you know.
但那个好难
I'm not a professional and haven't worked for five years.
我没有专业背景 而且这五年都是空白
Your experience will be a benefit.
你的实际经验绝对是个优势
I'm sure you'll find a good job.
你肯定可以找到一份好工作
Thanks.
谢谢
I'll help you in any way I can. Just let me know.
若有任何我帮得上忙的地方 请你尽管开口
Then, first is
那首先
your back.
你的腰
It needs to get better.
得把它治好
You're right.
是啊
It must have taken a lot of courage for her to ask,
她一定鼓足了勇气 才问出这个问题
but I couldn't give her an answer.
可我没办法给她答复
Being with Mitsuki
和美月在一起
would mean divorcing Ichiko and starting a new life.
意味着和小一离婚 开始全新的生活
A new family from zero with Mitsuki, and Hiro as a stepson.
和美月一起从零开始组建家庭 还带着小宏这个继子
I don't have enough determination to do that.
我还没有这么做的觉悟
Sorry.
对不起…
Was it only lust and attraction?
难道仅仅是情欲和诱惑？
No, it's more than that.
不 才不是这样
I also like her for who she is.
我也喜欢她这个人
I do, but
虽然喜欢
that kind of responsibility is too heavy for me.
但那种责任对我来说太沉重了
Wait.
等一下
What?
咦？
Hold on.
等等
Doesn't that make me
这样一来 我岂不是
a piece of shit?
成了渣男？
Otoya couldn't give me an answer.
二也没能给我答复
No, he was put off by my question.
不 我的问题让他反感了
My husband is six years older than me.
我的丈夫比我大六岁
We worked at the same company.
我们曾在同一家公司上班
That was the plan, but they said it couldn't be done.
原本是这样安排的 但他们说不行
He's good at his job,
他的工作能力很强
but he was quiet and unfriendly.
但性格文静冷漠
Some of the women had a crush on him,
有些女同事对他有好感
but a lot of them also said
但她们当中很多人也说
his attitude was too cold.
他的态度过于冷淡
We met when…
我们会有交集是因为…
Miss Sasazuka?
笹冢小姐？
A stalker?
有人跟踪？
Yeah. He is someone I know.
嗯 是我认识的人
It's not rare for stalkers to be a friend or someone you know.
跟踪狂是熟人 或者朋友的情况并不罕见
Should I take you home?
我送你回家吧？
-What? -It looks like he's still out there.
他好像还在外面
Let's leave through the back exit.
我们从后门走
As long as you don't find me bothersome.
要是你不介意的话
You're not a bother, but…
我当然不介意 可是…
I'll answer it.
我来接吧
Hello? I'm Shiro Kashiwagi. I work with Mitsuki.
喂？我是柏木志朗 笹冢小姐的同事
If you do this one more time,
如果你再纠缠
I'll report you to the company, the police and our security company.
我就向公司、警方 还有保安公司举报你
What?
什么？
He hung up.
他挂了
Let's go.
我们走吧
Thank you.
谢谢你
Worried about me, he would take me home when he had time.
他担心我 所以一有空就会送我回家
Hello.
辛苦了
Have things gotten better?
最近还好吗？
Yes. Thanks to you.
嗯 多亏有你
He hasn't called me at all lately.
他最近一个电话也没打来
That's good to hear.
那就好
Yes.
嗯
So I'm fine going home by myself.
现在我可以一个人回家了
Thank you for walking with me even though you're so busy.
谢谢你之前百忙中抽时间送我
It's fine.
没事
I'm glad it helped.
能帮上忙就好
Tell me if anything happens.
如果有什么事 尽管告诉我
-I will. -Good night.
-好 -晚安
But…
那个…
Can you go home with me today?
今天可以和我一起回家吗？
What? Is he--
那个人又…？
No, that's not it.
不是的
Well…
那个…
Would you like to have a cup of tea at my place?
你想去我家喝杯茶吗？
Come in. It's a little small.
请进 家里地方小
Thanks for inviting me.
打扰了
-Here. -Thank you.
-请用茶 -谢谢
Thanks for the tea.
多谢款待
Have some of these too.
也尝尝这个
What is this?
这是什么？
Mochi and red bean cookie.
红豆麻薯饼干
There's mochi and red bean in this?
里面有麻薯和红豆？
This is pretty good.
挺好吃的
1938?
1938年？
What? That old?
有那么古老吗？
Seven years before the war ended.
战争结束前七年
Can I have one more?
我能再吃一块吗？
Sure, go ahead.
当然
Be sure to lock up.
记得锁好门窗
Yes.
好
-Have a good night. -Good night.
-晚安
Thanks for having me.
多谢款待
He really left after a cup of tea.
真的喝了杯茶就走了
The first time he touched me was a long while
那天之后过了好久
from that day.
他才第一次碰我
-Welcome back. -I'm back.
-你回来了 -我回来了
Wasn't it cold? You didn't have dinner, right?
外面很冷吧？还没吃饭吧？
Mitsuki, can you get me a bottle opener?
美月 能帮我拿个开瓶器吗？
Sorry.
抱歉
-Here. -Thanks.
-给 -谢谢
Mitsuki.
美月
What is it?
什么事？
The company announced my transfer today.
今天公司宣布了我的调职令
I'll be transferred to Singapore in May for at least three years.
五月调去新加坡 至少会在那边待三年
I'll be counting on you to arrange for Hiro's classes there,
到了那边 安排小宏上学 还有打理家务什么的
our house and other things.
就都要拜托你了
Mitsuki, you've got a scary expression.
美月 你的表情好可怕
Sorry.
对不起
I was surprised.
就是很惊讶
Didn't I tell you there was a possibility I could get transferred?
我之前不是说过 有可能要调动工作吗？
You did.
你是说过
But isn't this too sudden?
但是不是有点太突然了？
Really?
有吗？
Even so, it has already been decided.
无论如何 已经决定了
-Hey. -Yeah?
-那… -嗯？
Can't you go alone?
你不能一个人去吗？
Why?
为什么？
Shouldn't my family support me at times like this?
这种时候 家人不该在身边支持我吗？
You're right.
话是没错
But this is an important time for Hiro.
但小宏现在正处在重要时期
Changing his environment right now will be too much for him.
这时改变环境 他可能适应不了
He finally got used to his class.
他好不容易才适应了现在的班级
But…
可是…
is this really about Hiro?
真的是因为小宏吗？
It's a good place to live, with a great education system.
那边居住环境好 教育系统也很优越
You can find facilities, schools, and teachers that meet Hiro's needs.
可以找到适合小宏的 机构、学校和老师
Over there, we can hire a maid to do the housework,
到了那边 我们可以雇人做家务
so things would be much easier for you.
你就能轻松很多
Isn't it you who doesn't want to leave?
不想离开的其实是你吧？
Using Hiro as an excuse.
还拿小宏当借口
I'm not going alone.
我肯定不会一个人去的
You already know that, don't you?
你自己也知道吧？
I've never restricted what you can do or complained about it.
我从没限制过你的行为 也没有抱怨过
Because I trust you.
那是因为我相信你
Be someone who can proudly call herself a mother.
当个问心无愧 名副其实的母亲吧
My husband knew…
我丈夫已经知道…
that I was having an affair.
我有外遇了
With no job and an affair, if I get a divorce,
没有工作 又有外遇 如果离婚的话
I could lose custody of Hiro.
我可能会失去小宏的监护权
This is an act of compassion from my husband.
我的丈夫这么做已算仁至义尽
My infidelity will go unquestioned if we end things now.
如果现在就停下 他便不会追究我的不忠
If I don't end things…
如果不停下…
Otoyan.
二也
So, what do you want to do for your birthday? Any food you want?
这次生日你想怎么过？想吃什么？
Oh, yeah.
对了
What's good? Sushi?
吃什么好呢？寿司？
Sushi is good. At Kitamori?
寿司很好啊 去北守吗？
Good idea. But can we get reservations?
好啊 但能预约到吗？
It's still a month away, so it should be okay. I'll call them.
还有一个月呢 应该没问题 我给他们打电话
Thanks.
多谢了
How's your back? Is it better?
你的腰怎么样了？好些了吗？
It hurts a little when I get up from bed.
起床时有点疼
MITSUKI KASHIWAGI GOOD MORNING.
（柏木美月 早上好）
CAN I SEE YOU THIS AFTERNOON?
（今天下午可以见面吗？）
THERE'S SOMETHING I NEED TO TELL YOU
（我有事要告诉你）
My husband is getting transferred.
我丈夫工作调动了
I think we're moving to Singapore in May.
我们五月份就要去新加坡
Really?
是吗？
Yeah.
是的
I wanted to tell you in person.
我想当面告诉你
And…
还有…
I'm sorry. I know you're busy.
对不起 我知道你很忙
But…
可是…
I see.
是这样啊
Wouldn't it be hard for you?
那你会很辛苦吧？
With Hiro and everything?
照顾小宏什么的
It will.
是啊
Hey, Otoya.
二也
Can we stay together a little longer?
我们能再多相处一段时间吗？
Of course.
当然可以
That's good.
太好了
Thanks for coming out today.
谢谢你今天来和我见面
It's so sad and lonely.
感觉好寂寞
I'm sad to hear she's leaving Japan, but it's sadder and lonelier
听说美月要离开日本 我很难过
to think I wasn't very shocked
但以后不能见面 却并没对我造成太大打击
about not being able to see her anymore.
这让我心里更加难过
A part of me was even relieved when she told me.
她告诉我要离开时 我甚至有种如释重负的感觉
YAY! I GOT RESERVATIONS FOR KITAMORI NEXT MONTH.
（耶！我订到了下个月的北守）
I'M SO EXCITED!
（好开心！）
YES! THANK YOU!
（太好了 谢谢你！）
It wasn't pretty today either.
今天的也不好看
Not at all.
才没有
For real?
真的吗？
-I think your arrangements are pretty. -No way.
-我觉得你插的花很好看 -一点也不
Your arrangements are always so beautiful.
你插的花总是那么漂亮
When March came,
到了三月
the days started to smell like spring.
空气中充满了春天的气息
I'd have tea with Mitsuki for an hour after the ikebana class.
花道课结束后 我会和美月喝一小时的茶
That's how we continued our relationship.
我们就这样维持着这段关系
We were both cautious and ignored the major issue.
我们俩都小心翼翼 避开那个重要的话题
It was like we were really good friends.
就像我们是好朋友一样
Otoya, I will quit the ikebana class after next week.
二也 下周之后 我就不会再去花道课了
Oh, right. Yeah.
是吗？是这样啊
I want to be together with you one last time.
我还想最后再和你约一次会
Me too.
我也是
Then let's go to our usual place next week.
那我们下周再去老地方吧
I'm looking forward to it.
我很期待
I'm home. Sorry for coming back late.
我回来了 抱歉回来晚了
Welcome back.
你回来啦
Hey, Ichiko.
小一
What?
什么事？
It's about next Thursday.
关于下周四的安排
Your birthday? I'm so excited about it.
你的生日？我很期待呢
Oh, yeah, I'm paying for dinner.
我请客哦
About that.
关于吃饭的事
It's okay. I'm getting my tax refund.
没事 我能拿到退税的钱
No, it's not that.
不是那个
I'm sorry.
对不起
You even made reservations, but I'm sorry.
你连餐厅都订好了 但真的很抱歉
I have a client dinner that I can't reschedule.
我和客户有个饭局 没办法改期
I see.
知道了
It sucks, but there's nothing we can do about it since it's work.
虽然很遗憾 但也没办法 毕竟是工作嘛
I'm really sorry.
真的很抱歉
To make up for it, let's make new plans and you pick the place.
我们可以重新安排 作为补偿 这次你来选地方
I'll make the reservations and pay for it.
我来预定 我请客
Think about where you want to go.
你考虑下想去哪里
I will.
我会考虑的
Then I'll go take a bath first.
那我先去洗个澡
ENTER PASSCODE
（输入密码）
EXCITED FOR NEXT WEEK
（期待下周 我也是 我先去开房间）
IT'S CROWDED TODAY SO TAKE YOUR TIME
（今天人多 你别急）
SHOULD WE GO SOMEWHERE ELSE?
（我们要不要去别的地方？）
Right now,
此时此刻
I probably look like a wife who discovered her husband is cheating.
我可能就像 发现丈夫有外遇的妻子
-Ichiko. I'm going to bed first. -Yeah?
-小一 我先去睡了 -嗯？
Okay. Good night.
晚安
Be sure to take a shower.
别忘了洗澡哦
I will, I will.
知道了
-Then, good night. -Good night.
-晚安
We're both adults, but we promised to celebrate our birthdays
虽然都是成年人 但我们约好了要珍视每年的生日
as a day to show our appreciation for each other.
一起庆生来表达对彼此的感激之情
We made sure to do it every year.
年年如此 雷打不动
At least until now…
可现在…
How could you, Otoyan?
你怎么能这样 二也？
CONTACT US - RESERVATIONS
（联系我们 预约）
YOUR MESSAGE: I'D LIKE TO MAKE A REQUEST
（您的留言：我有个请求）
CAN I MAKE A RESERVATION WITH REI
（下周四 3月21日）
FOR NEXT THURSDAY, MARCH 21?
（是否可以预约礼君？）
I ANSWERED "NO" TO GOING ALL THE WAY
（之前问卷中 “是否进行到底”的选项）
IN THE QUESTIONNAIRE,
（我选择了“否”）
BUT I'D LIKE TO CHANGE IT TO "YES."
（现在我想换成“是”）
SUBMIT YOUR MESSAGE
（发送信息）
YOUR MESSAGE HAS BEEN SUBMITTED.
（发送完毕）
Ichiko.
小一
I'll be late today, so go to bed without me.
今天我会晚回家 你先睡 不用等我
I have a meeting, so I might be late too.
我要见客户 可能也会晚回
Okay.
知道了
Otoyan.
二也
Happy birthday. Have a good day.
生日快乐 路上小心
Thank you. I will.
谢谢 我出门了
Our marriage isn't moral or proper.
我们的婚姻既不道德 也不合体统
It's warped and full of contradictions.
夫妻关系扭曲 而且充满了矛盾
And it might stay like this for a while.
或许还会这样持续一段时间
HAPPY BIRTHDAY
（生日快乐）
But isn't that okay?
但这也没关系吧？
Since we both want to stay in this marriage.
因为我们俩都想维持这段婚姻
Thank you for everything you've taught me.
感谢这段时间老师的教导
Mitsuki.
美月
Keep arranging flowers, even on your own.
哪怕一个人 也要继续插花哦
I will. Thank you.
我会的 谢谢
Take care.
多保重
I will.
好
Thank you.
谢谢
-We'll miss you.
-我们会想你的
-Thank you.
-谢谢
-It's going to be lonely without her. -Yeah.
-她走了 我们好孤单 -是啊
I'm going to miss you.
我会想你的
Really.
真的
Ichiko definitely knows that I'm seeing her tonight.
小一肯定知道我今晚要和情人见面
Ichiko, does it make you sad?
小一 你伤心吗？
Are you fed up with me?
你对我失望了吗？
Sorry I'm late.
抱歉我来晚了
Either way, Ichiko, this will be the last time.
无论如何 小一 这是最后一次了
It's been a while, Ichiko.
好久不见 一子
Yeah, it has.
是啊 好久不见
You look pretty today too.
你今天也很漂亮
Thank you.
谢谢
Ichiko.
一子
I need to ask to avoid any future issues.
为了避免以后造成任何麻烦 我想确认一下
I can go all the way today, right?
今天我可以进行到底 对吧？
Yes.
对
Please.
拜托了
As expected, Rei is really good with women.
礼君对待女性果然很有一套
I'm not as nervous as I was last time.
我没有上次那么紧张
Okay. I've decided.
好 我决定了
I'm going to really enjoy myself.
今天我要好好享受
I won't even think about Otoyan today.
完全不想二也的事
This is a present for you.
这是给你的礼物
What?
什么？
Thank you.
谢谢
-Can I open it? -Of course.
-可以打开吗？ -当然
Scissors and a kenzan flower holder set.
是花剪和剑山套装
Thank you.
谢谢你
Otoya.
二也
Thank you for everything.
谢谢你为我做的一切
This is our last night together.
今晚是我们最后一次在一起了
Otoya.
二也
Let's have sex.
我们做爱吧
Mitsuki.
美月
Let's stop…
我们…
doing this.
别再这样了
I'd…
我…
be happy if I could be friends with you.
如果可以成为你的朋友 我会很开心的
By friends, you mean…
朋友 你是说…
As friends, well…
做朋友 就像…
we listen to each other when we're having problems
遇到问题时 可以找对方倾诉
and support each other.
相互支持帮助
No, I mean…
不 我是说…
Mitsuki.
美月
Things have been a little weird between me and my wife.
我和我老婆最近有点别扭
It's not only because of our affair.
不仅仅是因为婚外情
But I think that's a big part of it.
但这应该是一个重要因素
So I want to fix my relationship with her.
所以我想修补我们的夫妻关系
So, both you and I,
所以 我们俩
let's start putting our own families first.
还是各自以家庭为重吧
And face what is really going on in our families.
把家里的事情处理好
I hope we can be friends who can talk with each other
希望我们能成为朋友 遇到困难
about our problems.
可以找对方倾诉
What do you think?
你觉得呢？
Mitsuki?
美月？
Does it feel good?
感觉很好吧？
Does it feel good making a pledge…
信誓旦旦要重建婚姻
to rebuild your marriage?
自我感觉很好吧？
Feeling relieved?
感觉松了口气？
That's not what I mean.
我不是那个意思
Sorry.
对不起
Did I say something weird?
我是不是说错什么了？
Mitsuki?
美月？
NEXT EPISODE
（下集预告）
Even after we break up, I don't want you to have sex with anyone else.
即使我们分手了 我也不愿你和别人上床
When Otoyan was stabbed in the genitals,
二也的私处被刺伤时
I was having crazy hot sex
我正在和风俗馆的男公关
with a gigolo from the brothel.
交欢缠绵
Fuck, it hurts.
好疼
A HUSBAND WHOSE LOVE ENDED WITH PAIN
（以痛苦结束恋情的丈夫）
I'm really happy I did it.
我很高兴选了你
A WIFE WHOSE HEART AND BODY WAS SOOTHED
（身心得到抚慰的妻子）
I think you simply hate it, right? That your husband has a lover.
感觉你其实很讨厌这样吧？ 讨厌你丈夫有情人
AFTER THE AUTHORIZED AFFAIR
（许可婚外恋之后）
We have to change, both you and I.
我们必须做出改变 你我都要改变
Will it still function properly?
以后功能还会正常吗？
COMES THE CONSTANT LIES
（随之而来的重重谎言）
I finally realized I hated the idea
我终于意识到
of you having a relationship with someone else.
我真的不希望你和别人发生关系
THIS IS A WORK OF FICTION.
（本故事纯属虚构）
Subtitle: Annie Chen
字幕翻译：纪小敏